Harold Bauer Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Writings by and about Harold Bauer (Box 4-5)
  - Speeches & Articles by Harold Bauer (Box 5)
    - HB and Wollstein, R.H. "Let the Amateur Make Music," clipping of article originally appearing in The Etude, condensed and reprinted in Readers' Digest, September 1931. One copy (Box-folder 5/20)
    - [Letter to members of the Beethoven Association], holograph, ink, dated 1935 Dec 30, 4 p. (Box-folder 5/21)
    - [The musical amateur] ("New York American, May 9, 1932."), holograph, ink, 10 p.; typed copy, undated, 6 p. (original copies); carbon copies of typed copy, with emendations, undated, 7 (Box-folder 5/22)
    - [Notes regarding Chopin's Polonaise, Liszt's Etude], holograph, undated, pencil, 1 p. (Box-folder 5/23)
    - "Notes on Robert Schumann," typed, undated, 3 p.; carbon copies of typed copy, 2 p. (Box-folder 5/24)
    - [Participation in music], holograph, undated, ink, 3 p. (Box-folder 5/25)
    - "Popular Music," holograph, undated, ink, 22 p. (Box-folder 5/26)
    - "Popular music," typed, undated, ink, 21 p. (Box-folder 5/27)
    - [Pythagorean monochord notes], holograph, undated, pencil, with sketches, 1 p. (Box-folder 5/28)
    - "Robert Schumann," holograph, undated, 20 p. (Box-folder 5/29)
    - "Schumann's Novelette, op. 99, no. 9," clipping from The Etude, August 1951, 4 p. (Box-folder 5/30)
    - "Self Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man," reprinted from The Musical Quarterly, vol. XXIX, no. 2, April 1943; p. 153-168. (Box-folder 5/31)
    - [Support for government funding for the arts], typed, with emendations in ink and in pencil, undated, 5 p. (Box-folder 5/32)
    - "Wm. Lym [?] Phelps: Autobiography/Ye Love of Change," holograph, undated, ink, 3 p. (Box-folder 5/33)
    - [Miscellaneous notes in HB's hand], 4 p. (Box-folder 5/34)
  - Speeches & Articles about Harold Bauer (Box 5)
    - Downes, Olin. "Harold Bauer." Typescript of lecture given as part of the "Bauer Memorial Broadcast," radio station WQXR, 1951 Mar 14, 3 p. (Box-folder 5/35)
    - Feldman, Abraham J. "Harold Bauer - an appreciation." Typescript of lecture given at the "Harold Bauer Memorial Concert," Hartt College of Music (Hartford, CT), 1951 May 17, 2 p. (Box-folder 5/36)
    - Fulles músicals. Revista patrocinada per l'Associació de Música da Camera, 1927 Oct 15 (v. 1, no. 1) (Barcelona, Spain), 24 p. Contains biography of HB on p. 4. (Box-folder 5/37)
    - Heylbut, Rose. "Education as Emancipation/A Conference with Harold Bauer," clipping from The Etude, May 1948, 2 p. (Box-folder 5/38)
    - [Volpe, Marie (?)]. "Marie Volpe on Music," transcript of interview with HB, conducted in Miami, 1948 Feb 21; typed, 7 p. (Box-folder 5/39)
- Writings, Other (Box 6-7)
  The Writings, Other series consists of two subseries: Beethoven Association and Other. This series is represented by periodicals and publications related to Harold Bauer or his compositions.
  Arranged by author or title.
  - Beethoven Association material (Box 6)
    - Constitution and By-laws of the Beethoven Association, printed pamphlet, dated April 1923 (?). (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Beethoven Association Annual Report, bound pamphlet, dated April 1925, 29 p. (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Beethoven Association Annual Report, bound pamphlet, dated April 1926, 26 p. (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Beethoven Association Annual Report, bound pamphlet, dated April 1927, 23 p. (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Beethoven Association Annual Report, bound pamphlet, dated May 1928, 25 p. (two copies). (Box-folder 6/5)
    - Beethoven Association Annual Report, bound pamphlet, dated May 1929, 28 p. (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Beethoven Association Annual Report, bound pamphlet, dated June 1930, 28 p. (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Beethoven Association Annual Report, bound pamphlet, dated June 1931, 37 p. (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Beethoven Association Annual Report, bound pamphlet, dated June 1932, 30 p. (Box-folder 6/9)
    - Beethoven Association Annual Report, bound pamphlet, dated June 1933, 43 p. (Box-folder 6/10)
    - Beethoven Association Annual Report, bound pamphlet, dated July 1934, 36 p. (Box-folder 6/11)
    - Beethoven Association Annual Report, bound pamphlet, dated September 1935, 30 p. (two copies). (Box-folder 6/12)
    - Beethoven Association Annual Report, bound pamphlet, dated July 1936, 36 p. (Box-folder 6/13)
    - Beethoven Association Annual Report, bound pamphlet, dated August 1937, 34 p. (Box-folder 6/14)
    - Beethoven Association Annual Report, bound pamphlet, dated August 1938, 32 p. (two copies). (Box-folder 6/15)
  - Other (Box 7)
    - L'Aide affectueuse aux Musiciens, Members' report, June 1918, 12 p. (Box-folder 7/1)
    - American Federation of Musicians, Official Journal of, Local 802, Associated Musicians of Greater New York, May 1941 (v. XV, no. 7), 27 p. (Box-folder 7/2)
    - American Federation of Musicians, Official Journal of, Local 802, Associated Musicians of Greater New York, October 1941 (v. XV, no. 12), p. 1-12. (Box-folder 7/3)
    - [American Piano Company publicity brochure ("Pianos old and new")]. Cleveland: Caxton Company, 1924, 14 p. (Box-folder 7/4)
    - "Appreciation of Music" Bulletin, the South Orange-Maplewood (NJ?) Adult School, dated 1940 Jan 23. Photoreproduced program notes of original typescript, 2 p. (Box-folder 7/5)
    - The Bohemians/By-laws/List of members, printed pamphlet, dated December 1934, 32 p. (Box-folder 7/6)
    - Elwell, Herbert. "The Search for method in Modernism," lecture delivered at Oberlin Conservatory, 1949 Nov 15. Photoreproduced copy, 15 p. (Box-folder 7/7)
    - [Ernest E. Gottlieb Company sales catalog (No. XI: "Musicology/Part one")], undated, 28 p. (Box-folder 7/8)
    - Hibberd, Lloyd. "Estampie and Stantipes," reprinted from Speculum, April 1944 (v. XIX, no. 2), by the Mediaeval Academy of America (Cambridge, MA), p. 222-249. Inscribed to HB by the author. (Box-folder 7/9)
    - Hickman, C.N. "A Description of a new grand piano and comparison with the present grand action." Carbon copies of original typescript and photo- reproductions, undated, 30 p. (Box-folder 7/10)
    - Keefer, Lubov. "The Influence of Adam Mickiewicz on the Ballades of Chopin," reprinted from The American Slavic and East European Review, May 1946 (v. V, nos. 12-13), p. 38-50. (Box-folder 7/11)
    - Keilhau, Wilhelm. "Edvard Grieg... - A Chapter of Norwegian history," reprinted from The Norseman, 1943 (v. I, no. 3), 20 p. (Box-folder 7/12)
    - The "Last" Stradivarius Cello. Printed pamphlet, copyrighted by Russell B. Kingman, 1944, 8 p. (Box-folder 7/13)
    - [Manhattan School of Music Concert and Placement Bureau publicity pamphlet ("Treasure House of Talent")], undated. Contains photo of HB. (Box-folder 7/14)
    - Newman, H.H. Evolution, Genetics, and Eugenics: "Evidences from Embryology" (Chapter IX); "Critique of the Recapitulation Theory" (Chapter X) (from Scott, W.B., The Theory of Evolution, The Macmillan Company, 1917) (excerpt). No publication data included. Inscribed to HB by Roy Fraser. (Box-folder 7/15)
    - Nossig, Alfred. J.J. Paderewski. Leipzig: Hermann Seemann Nachfolger, n.d., 33 p. (Box-folder 7/16)
    - Pages from Schubert's Diary. Monograph printed by the Columbia Phonograph Company for the Advisory Board of the Schubert Centennial, dated 1928 Nov 18, 31 p. (Box-folder 7/17)
    - Pochon, Alfred. Musique d'autrefois/Interprétation d'aujourd'hui. Geneva: Édition Henn, 1943, 72 p. Inscribed to HB by the author. (Box-folder 7/18)
    - [Pythagorean monochord notes]: carbon copies of original typescript, excerpted from Dowland, John, Andreas ornithoparcus/His micrologues or Introduction containing the Art of Singing... Also the Dimensions and Perfect use of the Monochord according to Guido Aretinus (London, n.p., 1609), 3 p. Contains annotations and sketches in pencil. (Box-folder 7/19)
    - [Pythagorean monochord notes]: typescript of excerpts from Taylor, Thomas (translator), From Iamblicus life of Pythagoras or Pythagoric Life (London: A.J. Vulpy, 1818), 4 p. (Box-folder 7/20)
    - Riemenschneider, Albert. Some Aspects of the Use of Flutes in the Works of J.S. Bach. Monograph, printed by the Music Division of the Library of Congress (Washington, DC: U.S. Government Printing Office, 1950), 23 p. (Box-folder 7/21)
    - Sachs, Curt. The Commonwealth of Art. Monograph of lecture delivered at the Library of Congress, 1949 Apr 25 (Washington, DC: U.S. Government Printing Office, 1950), 19 p. (Box-folder 7/22)
    - Schenck, Janet D. Adventure in Music. A Reminiscence. Manhattan School of Music 1918-1960. Published by the Manhattan School of Music, New York, 1961, 111 p. (Box-folder 7/23)
    - Spivacke, Harold. "Paganiniana," offprint from The Library of Congress Quarterly Journal of Current Acquisitions, February 1945 (v. II, no. 2) (Washington, DC: U.S. Government Printing Office, 1945), 19 p. (Box-folder 7/24)
    - Taylor, Robert Lewis. [Three articles on Percy Grainger], clippings from The New Yorker, early 1948, 16 p.; photoreproduced copy of these, 21 p. (Box-folder 7/25)
    - Tibbett, Lawrence. "My Most Momentous Musical Moment," clipping from The Etude, c. 1942, 2 p. (Box-folder 7/26)
    - Van Loon, Hendrik Willem. This I believe! Pamphlet printed by the American Unitarian Association (Boston, MA), May 1943, 1 p. (two copies). (Box-folder 7/27)
    - Van Loon, Hendrik Willem. To have or to be - take your choice. New York: John Day Company, 1932, 28 p. Inscribed by the author on front cover. (Box-folder 7/28)
- Clippings, 1887-1951 (Box 8)
  The Clippings series is represented by printed matter relating to Harold Bauer's music or performances (number of items in each folder appear within parentheses following the folder name).
  Arranged chronlogically.
  - Clippings, 1887-1919 (26) (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Clippings, 1920-1924 (20) (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Clippings, 1925-September 1926 (38) (Box-folder 8/3)
  - Clippings, October 1926 (55) (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Clippings, November 1926-December 1927 (27) (Box-folder 8/5)
  - Clippings, 1928-1929 (25) (Box-folder 8/6)
  - Clippings, 1930-1932 (48) (Box-folder 8/7)
  - Clippings, 1933-1934 (19) (Box-folder 8/8)
  - Clippings, 1935-1938 (28) (Box-folder 8/9)
  - Clippings, 1939-1942 (37) (Box-folder 8/10)
  - Clippings, 1943 (47) (Box-folder 8/11)
  - Clippings, 1944-1945 (26) (Box-folder 8/12)
  - Clippings, 1946-1950 (27) (Box-folder 8/13)
  - Clippings, 1951- (9) (Box-folder 8/14)
  - Clippings: Obituaries (17) (Box-folder 8/15)
  - Clippings regarding Harold Bauer: His Book (47) (Box-folder 8/16)
  - Clippings regarding F. Chopin (27) (Box-folder 8/17)
  - Clippings regarding I. Paderewski (18) (Box-folder 8/18)
  - Clippings, miscellaneous, A-N (62) (Box-folder 8/19)
  - Clippings, miscellaneous, O-R (47) (Box-folder 8/20)
  - Clippings, miscellaneous, S-Z (13) (Box-folder 8/21)
  - Clippings, undated (69) (Box-folder 8/22)
- Publicity (Box 9-11)
  The Publicity series consists of three subseries: Programs, Bound; Programs, Unbound; and Tour Materials (number of items in each folder appear within parentheses following the folder name). The bound programs were originally contained in five leather-bound volumes.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Programs, Bound (Box 9)
    - "Programmes, 1892-1905" (Box-folder 9/1)
    - "Programmes, 1905-1909" (Box-folder 9/2)
    - "Programmes, 1909-1911" (Box-folder 9/3)
    - "American programmes, 1900-1904" (Box-folder 9/4)
    - "American programmes, 1905-1908" (Box-folder 9/5)
  - Programs, Unbound, 1899-1949 (Box 10)
    - Printed programs, -1899 (1) (Box-folder 10/1)
    - Printed programs, 1910-12 (31) (Box-folder 10/2)
    - Printed programs, 1913 (31) (Box-folder 10/3)
    - Printed programs, 1914-19 (9) (Box-folder 10/4)
    - Printed programs, 1920-26 (15) (Box-folder 10/5)
    - Printed programs, 1927-29 (17) (Box-folder 10/6)
    - Printed programs, 1930 (16) (Box-folder 10/7)
    - Printed programs, 1931-32 (19) (Box-folder 10/8)
    - Printed programs, 1933-34 (15) (Box-folder 10/9)
    - Printed programs, 1935-36 (14) (Box-folder 10/10)
    - Printed programs, 1937-39 (10) (Box-folder 10/11)
    - Printed programs, 1940-49 (31) (Box-folder 10/12)
    - Printed programs, undated: solo recitals by HB (17) (Box-folder 10/13)
    - Printed programs, undated: recitals by HB with others (17) (Box-folder 10/14)
    - Printed programs by others, with references to HB (21) (Box-folder 10/15)
    - Miscellaneous programs (3) (Box-folder 10/16)
  - Material Regarding Concert Tours, 1936-1944 (Box 11)
    - "Press book[s] for HB," (2 items) containing biographical information; one photo- reproduction of typescript; the other printed. (Box-folder 11/1)
    - Tour lists, itineraries, 14 p., typed and in pencil. (Box-folder 11/2)
    - Tour programs, 1936, 36 p. (Box-folder 11/3)
    - Tour programs, 1937, 53 p. (Box-folder 11/4)
    - Tour programs, 1938, 37 p. (Box-folder 11/5)
    - Tour programs, 1939, 16 p. (Box-folder 11/6)
    - Tour programs, 1940, 21 p. (Box-folder 11/7)
    - Tour programs, 1941, 18 p. (Box-folder 11/8)
    - Tour programs, 1942, 10 p. (Box-folder 11/9)
    - Tour programs, 1943-44, 18 p. (Box-folder 11/10)
    - Miscellaneous publicity, 20 p. (Box-folder 11/11)
- Awards & Certificates (Box 15-16)
  The Awards and Certificates series is represented by such documents given to Harold Bauer in recognition of his achievements.
  Arranged by subject.
  - Certificate naming HB a "Chevalier" of the Ordre National de la Légion d'Honneur, issued at Paris, 1927 Jan 12 & 14. (Box-folder 16/1)
  - Certificate from Alfonso XIII, King of Spain, and Maria Cristina, Queen Regent, naming HB a "Caballero" of the Ordem Española de Isabel la Católica, issued 1901 Sep 22. (Box-folder 16/2)
  - Handwritten document honoring HB, signed by the Queen Regent of Portugal, dated 1902 Dec 1; original envelope included. (Box-folder 15/20)
  - Certificate from the Ministère de l'Instruction Publique et des Beaux-Arts (Paris, France), naming HB an "Officier d'Académie"; issued at Paris, 1903 Mar 1. (Box-folder 15/21)
  - Certificate from the Ministère de l'Instruction Publique et des Beaux-Arts (Paris, France), naming HB an "Officier d'Instruction Publique"; issued at Paris, 1908 May 23. (Box-folder 15/22)
  - Certificate of honorary membership in Mu Phi Delta music fraternity, Colgate University chapter (Hamilton, NY), issued 1937 Apr 20. (Box-folder 15/23)
  - Certificate of receipt from the Library of Congress, issued at Washington, DC, 1935 Apr 17, for HB's gift of a photoreproduced, bound score of L. van Beethoven's Grand Fugue (for pf, 4 hands), op. 134. (Box-folder 15/24)
  - Certificate of receipt from the New York Public Library, issued at New York, 1945 May 11, for HB's gift of a score of L. van Beethoven's Grande Fugue, op. 133 (Vienna, 1827). (Box-folder 15/25)
- Miscellany (Box 11)
  The Miscellany series consists of two subseries: Legal & Financial and Other.
  Arranged by subject or format.
  - Legal & Financial Papers (Box 11)
    - Birth certificate, issued at London, 1917 June 13. (Box-folder 11/12)
    - Certificate of (American) naturalization, issued at New York, 1924 Jul 10. (Box-folder 11/13)
    - Miscellaneous legal, financial papers, 13 p. (Box-folder 11/14)
  - Other (Box 11)
    - Recordings and piano rolls: lists, related publicity, 9 p. (Box-folder 11/15)
    - Invitations (2 items) to a dinner sponsored by the Worshipful Company of Musicians at "Stationers' Hall, E.C.," dated 1926 Oct 26 and 1927 Oct 25 (Box-folder 11/16)
    - Stamp collection: postage stamps honoring composers, a writer (A. Pushkin), and music in general; contains 21 stamps; dated "Omaha, 4/13/44." (Box-folder 11/17)
    - Other, 15 items. (Box-folder 11/18)
- Iconography (Box 12, 14A, 15, 17)
  The Iconography series consists of five subseries: Harold Bauer Alone; Harold Bauer with Others; Photographs of Others; Photographs, Other; and Artwork. When indicated, name and location of photographer, in parentheses, and any other written or printed indications, in quotation marks and in parentheses.
  - Photographs of Harold Bauer Alone (Box 12, 14A, 15)
    - HB as young boy, with violin (Offenbach/New York) (Box-folder 12/1)
    - HB as young boy, framed photograph, dated 1886 [FRAGILE] (Box-folder 14A/1)
    - HB, dated 1896 (Elliott & Fry, London) (Box-folder 12/2)
    - HB as young man ("Property of Loudon G. Charlton/Carnegie Hall/New York.") (Box-folder 15/1)
    - HB as young man, reprinted (halftone) photo (Box-folder 12/3)
    - HB at piano, dated 1897 (Herm. Hamnqvist, Stockholm) (Box-folder 12/4)
    - HB (Window & Grove, London) (Box-folder 12/5)
    - HB, inscribed to Gottfried Mann (?), dated 1898 (Photographie Société anonyme / Kosmos, Amsterdam) (Box-folder 12/6)
    - HB as young man ("about 1900") (Box-folder 15/2)
    - HB aboard the S.S. France ("Sept 26 - Oct 2nd 1931") (Box-folder 12/7)
    - HB at piano (Apeda/New York) (Box-folder 12/8)
    - Framed collection of photographs (11) of HB [FRAGILE] (Box-folder 14A/3)
    - HB at age 50, framed photograph [FRAGILE] (Box-folder 14A/4)
    - HB (Selmer Norland/Kristiania) (Box-folder 12/9)
    - HB with cigarette ("29/MP") (Box-folder 12/10)
    - HB at Bar Harbor, ME (Box-folder 12/11)
    - HB ("...as Meyerbeer, April 28, 1933 (his 60th birthday)/At the `Opera Ball' (benefit for Opera)") (Albert R. Dupont/New York) (Box-folder 12/12)
    - HB (at "Manhattan School/May 1948") (Box-folder 12/13)
    - HB (Kossuth/Wheeling, WV) (Box-folder 12/14)
    - HB seated, in profile (C. Bennette Moore/New Orleans) (Box-folder 15/3)
    - HB in profile (Palomba/Napoli) (Box-folder 15/4)
    - HB ("Last and best mature photo ... by Argianni") (Box-folder 12/15)
    - HB (at "Naples, Italy") (Box-folder 12/16)
    - HB with book (Box-folder 15/5)
    - HB at piano ("Miami Herald Photo/Miami, Florida/Winter 1945") (Box-folder 12/17)
    - HB (at "University of Miami") (Box-folder 12/18)
    - HB ("Apeda/New York") (Box-folder 12/19)
    - HB (3 items; Arnold Genthe/New York) (Box-folder 12/20)
    - HB (2 items; John Haley/Hartford, CT) (Box-folder 12/21)
    - HB in Paris (3 items) (Box-folder 12/22)
    - HB (2 items; unidentified photographers) (Box-folder 12/23)
    - Photoreproduction of drawing of HB as a young boy, with violin, by "J.M.B[.,19]88" (Box-folder 15/6)
    - Photo of drawing of HB by Charles Boiry, Paris, 1910 (Box-folder 12/24)
    - Photo of drawing of HB by Katharine M. Gericke, 1932 (Box-folder 15/7)
  - Photographs of Harold Bauer with Others (Box-folder 12, 15, 17)
    - Mr. & Mrs. HB at "Sedgemere," their home at St. James, Long Island, New York (Box-folder 12/25)
    - HB, O. Gabrilowitsch (verso: "First 2-piano artists in U.S.A.") (Box-folder 12/26)
    - HB, P. Casals, ? (verso: "on tour") (Box-folder 12/27)
    - HB, F. Kreisler, J. Hofmann (at Seal Harbor, Maine) (Box-folder 12/28)
    - HB, B. Huberman, F. Salmond, L. Tertis (autographed by all pictured) (Box-folder 12/29)
    - Group photo (including P. Grainger, etc.) ("Moszkowski Benefit Concert/Met Opera House [,] Dec 1923") (Box-folder 12/30)
    - Group photo (including G. Barrère, etc.) ("Moszkowski Benefit Concert - Party at the home of Ernest Shelling. New York.") (Pack Bros./New York) (Box-folder 15/8)
    - Publicity calendar for the Baldwin Piano Company for 1931, including photographs of W. Gieseking, J. Iturbi, J. Lhevinne, etc. (Box-folder 12/31)
    - Group photo (including G. Barrère, L. Auer, F. Damrosch, et al.) of the "annual meeting dinner of the Beethoven Association and the 50th birthday of our president Harold Bauer. The Biltmore [New York, NY] April 28, 1923." (Photo by Drucker & Baltes Co.) (Box-folder 17/1)
  - Photographs of Others (Box 12, 15)
    - Wynne Pyle Bauer (2 items; Arnold Genthe/New York) (Box-folder 12/32)
    - Wynne Pyle Bauer ("Arpeda" on verso [=Apeda (photographer)/New York ?]) (Box-folder 12/33)
    - Photo of drawing of L. van Beethoven (Box-folder 12/34)
    - L. van Beethoven: tomb (Box-folder 12/35)
    - David Bistham (inscribed, dated 1910) (Box-folder 12/36)
    - Ernest Bloch (inscribed to HB, "San Francisco, Mar 1928") (Box-folder 15/9)
    - Walter Damrosch (2 items: one unsigned; the other inscribed to HB, "Dec. 28/1922") (Box-folder 15/10)
    - Claude Debussy (inscribed, dated August 1916) (Box-folder 12/37)
    - Wilhelm Gericke [?] (inscribed "With love from Paula and Katharine Gericke / Vienna, April 1930") (Selzer/Vienna) (Box-folder 15/11)
    - Yvette Guilbert (inscribed to HB) (Marcia Stein) (Box-folder 15/12)
    - Photo of drawing of Ferdinand von Hiller (Box-folder 12/38)
    - Photo of drawing of Joseph Joachim (Box-folder 12/39)
    - Franz Liszt (Louis Held/Weimar) (Box-folder 15/13)
    - Lillian Nordica (inscribed to "Mrs. Beringer", dated 1894) (W. Höffert/Berlin) (Box-folder 12/40)
    - Ignace Jan Paderewski (inscribed "New York/Nov 2nd, 1907/W. Pyle") (G. Nitsche/Lausanne) (Box-folder 12/41)
    - Anton Rubinstein; contains handwritten quotation from Plato on verso (J. Ganz / Bruxelles) (Box-folder 12/42)
    - Franz Schubert: memorial (Box-folder 12/43)
    - Photos of drawings of Robert and Clara Schumann (4 items) (Box-folder 12/44)
    - Leopold Stokowski (inscribed to HB) (Box-folder 15/14)
    - Rabindranath Tagore (autographed) (E.S. Curtis/Seattle) (Box-folder 15/15)
    - Jacques and Marguerite Thibaud (inscribed to "Marie"), "New York, 1917." (Box-folder 12/45)
    - Miscellaneous/unidentified photos of drawings/lithographs (2 items) (Box-folder 12/46)
    - Postcards regarding L. van Beethoven, E. Grieg, F. Liszt, W.A. Mozart, F. Schubert, R. Schumann; the Vienna Opera House, and the Vienna History Museum (34 items) (Box-folder 12/47)
  - Photographs, Other (Box 12)
    - Plaster, bronze castings of HB's hands (2 items) [FRAGILE] (Box-folder 12/48)
    - HB's Baldwin piano (Box-folder 12/49)
    - HB's medals (Box-folder 12/50)
    - Bust of HB by Brenda Putnam (3 items) (Box-folder 12/51)
    - "Sedgemere," St. James, Long Island, New York (Box-folder 12/52)
    - Photo of drawing of female head and shoulders titled "Appassionata" (Box-folder 12/53)
    - Photo of drawing of nude female torso titled "Moonlight Sonata" (Box-folder 12/54)
  - Artwork (Box 12, 14A, 15)
    - Self-portrait of HB, in blue pencil, titled "David and Goliath," dated 1926 Jun 12 (Box-folder 12/55)
    - Drawing of HB, in ink and watercolor, by Bento Barboza (São Paulo, Brazil, 1904) (Box-folder 12/56)
    - Drawing of HB by Kulh Brut, in ink (Box-folder 15/16)
    - Drawing (caricature) of HB by Massaguer, in pencil, dated 1933 (Box-folder 15/17)
    - Silhouette drawing of HB, P.Casals, in ink ("Van-Castelle, Spain") (Box-folder 12/57)
    - Silhouette drawing of HB (reproduction), dated Paris, May 1901 (Box-folder 14A/2)
    - L. van Beethoven: lithograph of the composer "in his Study," by Carl Schloesser (Box-folder 15/18)
    - Franz Schubert: lithographs (2 items) by the same artist, signed: a portrait of the composer, dated 1928; and a view of the composer's home (Box-folder 15/19)
- Realia (Box 13-14)
  The Realia series is represented by artifacts from the Harold Bauer Collection.
  Note: Two additional medals awarded to HB (one medal, presented by the Philharmonic Society of London, 1912; and one silver medal) and included in the collection are presently housed in the Musical Instrument Vault's Map Case. Photographs of all medals awarded to HB can be found in Box 12, Folder 50; one photograph of the plaster castings of HB's hands, contained in Box 13 of the collection, can be found in Box 12, Folder 48.
  - Plaster casting of HB's hands [* FRAGILE *] (Box-folder 13/1)
  - Metronome, with key, in chamois pouch. (Box-folder 14/1)
  - Medal, boxed, inscribed "Sciencias, Letras e Artes" (Lisbon, Portugal). (Box-folder 14/2)